# Katie Antlitz

## Full Stack Software Developer

Address Shorewood, IL, 60404

E-mail ksantlitz@gmail.com

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/katinthecode

**WWW** http://www.katinthecode.com/

A creative and curious full stack developer with over nine years of experience developing and maintaining many different projects. I've worked through the full development cycle from use cases and functional requirements to the end product. I continue to learn and experiment with new technologies. I am interested in finding a company with a good culture that I can call home for the long term.

## **Work History**

2022-03 - Current

#### **Software Developer**

Relativity, Chicago, IL

- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving functionality.
- Documented architecture and workflows for our projects.
- Code bug fixes and technical debt user stories using React, c#, .NET, and SQL.

2021-07 - 2022-02

#### Senior .NET Software Developer, Full-Stack

Stratus Data Systems, New York, NY

Stratus Data Systems is a company that builds web apps for the real estate industry.

- Troubleshoot and resolve functional and performance related issues
- Working on new enhancements and defect fixes for multiple mature applications using Javascript, C#.NET, SQL, and Mongo
- Testing and reviewing teammates' code

2020-10 - 2021-07

### **Software Developer**

Utilidata, Providence, RI

Utilidata is a company that creates real-time software that helps to optimize the settings of electric grids.

- Assisted in developing new software that will work with smart devices
- Assisted in creating Python APIs designed to read information from devices
- Created Java Spring Boot API that allows users to change settings on devices
- Created Python scripts that stream data from csv files in an AWS bucket and inserts it into Redshift
- Testing and reviewing teammates' code

2019-07 - 2020-10

#### Research and Development Software Developer

Performance Livestock Analytics, Ames, IA

PLA is a technology company that provides farm management tools in the livestock industry.

- Worked on PLA's research and development team creating ways to send data from RFID tag readers to insert into system using MQTT, Python, and GoLang
- Created new API to access and update animal tag information
- Helped to create new Animal Health project using Swift and MySQL for iOS
- Work with IOT devices to manage livestock
- Work with Android development to create app that scans <u>RFID</u> tags and updates animal information using Bluetooth devices
- Research ways to connect and use new technologies

#### 2016-11 - 2019-04

#### **Senior Software Developer**

ICOMM, Forest Park, Illinois

ICOMM is a company that handles telecommunications for clients, including mobile devices, voice systems, help desk support, and expense management. I worked on a small team of developers to create external and internal applications, console applications for data loading, reports detailing client expenses and usage, and worked with many different vendors to set up delivery of invoices through EDI.

- Worked on ETL console application with webpages that allow internal users to import different formats of documentation including comma delimited, XLS, and XML formats and map each column to a database table and column specified by user. The system then saves this information and automatically starts importing files as they are uploaded.
- Worked on development of Ordering Portals tailored to needs of different external clients using C#.NET, .NET Framework, WebForms, HTML5, Bootstrap, and SQL
- Created ETL to automate ServiceNow data importing and SSRS reports to display employee statistics
- Added features to legacy code including ability to request automated invoices, dynamically build Excel spreadsheet reports for telecommunication usage.
- Maintained legacy desktop and Windows applications using VB.NET, .NET Framework, WebForms/WinForms, HTML, and SQL stored procedures
- Maintained production and test environments using Azure and internal Windows 2012 servers
- Introduced best practices to improve software documentation, team planning, release processes and customization of applications based on client needs
- Mentored junior and senior level developers

#### 2014-11 - 2016-08

#### **Internal Applications Developer**

CSG Government Solutions, Chicago, IL

CSG Government Solutions provides consultation to help state governments modernize critical program enterprises. I was part of a two person team that worked on supporting internal applications. These applications included the internal website, learning management system, Android applications and console

applications. I also created reports as needed and worked to fix any bugs that came up.

- Created new Android app that contained and maintained library of legal documentation needed by the consultants, including feedback and usage reports in order to monitor most used documents
- Created and lead development of a SCORM compliant Learning Management System using C#.NET, WebForms, HTML5, JavaScript, Outlook REST APIs, and WebEx REST APIs
- Created SSRS reports using stored procedures
- Redesigned internal SharePoint website using CSS, HTML, and JavaScript
- Maintained and added new features to legacy code

#### 2012-01 - 2014-11

#### **Software Developer**

Applied Systems, Epic Accounting, University Park, IL

Applied Systems is an insurance software company. I worked on the accounting team for their Epic software. I started as a junior developer working on small fixes and moving my way into a more mid-level development role working on different features. I worked through three full project lifecycles of Epic.

- Worked on project to rewrite receipts, disbursement, and voucher functionality to include ability to override completed receipts by administrators and keep track of previous changes using VB.NET, .NET, WinForms, and SQL on distributed system, Epic
- Worked on project to batch process transactions
- Lead feature project to improve check printing for disbursements
- Maintained legacy code for Epic
- Worked directly with large clients to create new features
- Worked on test agile team before Applied fully converted
- Mentored junior developers

#### **Education**

#### 2018-10 - 2022-12

## **Computer Science**

DePaul University - Chicago, IL

#### 2009-09 - 2012-06

#### **Computer Information Systems**

DeVry University - Downers Grove, IL

- Graduated Cum Laude
- Member of Alpha Sigma Lambda National Honors Society
- Dean's List

## **Personal Hobbies**

Virtual Reality and gaming

Working on redesigning my website, www.katinthecode.com using HTML5, PHP, MySQL

Cozy mysteries

Technology

## Skills

Self-motivated professional	
	Excellent
Programming	Very Good
Hardware and software installation	Excellent
Technical Support	Very Good
API development	Good
SQL	Excellent
Python	Average
Java	Good
C#.NET	Very Good
Mentoring	Good
IOS development	Average
Android development	Average